TIFFANY HUEY

▼ tiffanyannhuey@gmail.com

tiffanyannhuey.com

402-301-9586

in tiffanyhuey

tiffanyannhuey

Versatile Web Developer with experience developing and managing complex web applications. Highly organized, self-motivated, and conscientious coder able to adapt to changing priorities and maintain a strong work ethic with creativity and humor. Skilled in Front-end Development, SASS/LESS/CSS, Angular, and Responsive Web Design.

Skills

Web Technologies & Frameworks

Angular JavaScript/ Typescript

Symfony

PHP

Bootstrap

HTML/CSS

- - - - - - -

Ruby on Rails

Database and ORM

MySQL

PostgreSQL

ActiveRecord

Versioning and Other Tools

Git

Bitbucket

Pantheon

CMS and E-Commerce Platforms

Wordpress

Drupal

Miva Merchant

Core Competencies

Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC)

Test Driven Development REST/CRUD Applications

Agile Development

Project Management

Search Engine Optimization (SEO)

Employment

Fortune builders

Front End Developer

- Technologies used: Wordpress, Javascript (jQuery, Typescript, RxJS), Angular, PHP, MySql, Symfony, HTML5, CSS3, Gulp, Bitbucket, Git
- Develop new features and maintain multiple Angular applications and Wordpress plugins.
- Collaborate with a team of four developers using Bitbucket/Git for version control and peer review.
- Create API endpoints on Symfony framework and test using Postman
- Consume RESTful web services using Http Client in Angular services.
- Update router to perform navigation between components in Angular, along with separate router for mobile version of Angular application using ng-device-detector.
- Work in concert with UI/UX designers to develop webpages from Figma mockups, establish feedback loop to ensure feasibility of design.
- Develop User Interface (UI) components with HTML5, SASS/SCSS, Bootstrap, Angular Material, JavaScript, jQuery, and AJAX, build out modular SASS library for scalable and streamlined design.

AbacusNext Oct. 2018 to Dec. 2018

Front End Web Developer

- Technologies: Wordpress, Drupal 7, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Javascript, jQuery, PHP, Git, Pantheon
- Code responsive landing page variations for A/B testing, using Git and Pantheon for version control.
- Execute UX/UI and CRO updates across company sites, leveraging Google Lighthouse, Hotjar, Google Analytics, and SEMRush to monitor performance.
- Consolidate tracking data and scripts via Google Tag Manager to streamline site scripts, audit to ensure web pages meet SEO criteria.
- Resolve Drupal Salesforce-web-to-lead data integration issues within first week of employment.

Miva June 2017 to Sept. 2018

Web Developer

- Technologies: HTML, CSS, Javascript, jQuery, phpMyAdmin, MySQL, PHP, Cloudflare
- Build new features and solutions for mid-to-enterprise level e-commerce websites, pioneer new projects such as multi-add-to-cart functionality with Miva native suggestive search.
- Code webpages from Photoshop mockups, debug and resolve website issues, and provide data & system analysis.
- Construct custom feeds per client specifications and set up cron job to run scheduled feeds.
- Implement third party integrations, including custom ERPs, Power Reviews, SearchSpring, Wordpress, and Mailchimp.
- Optimize websites for SEO, updates to .htaccess and website files to reduce page load time.

Rosemont Media June 2015 to Jan. 2017

Rosemont Media Web Project Manager

- Technologies: Wordpress, HTML, CSS, Google Webmaster Tools, Google Analytics, Basecamp
- Main client point-of-contact for all new website build projects throughout the website development life cycle.
- Implement client requests via Wordpress backend and leverage teleconference tools to demonstrate Wordpress capabilities to end-users.
- Prepare sitemap and .htaccess files in conjunction with website launches and monitor/update links using Google Webmaster tools.
- Identify key website traffic areas and SEO optimization opportunities to improve website performance metrics.

Education

Dev Bootcamp

Nov. 2016 to Apr. 2017

Mar. 2019 to Mar. 2020

Languages and frameworks: Git workflow/version control, Ruby, JavaScript (object-oriented JavaScript, jQuery, and AJAX), Test-Driven Development (RSpec and Jasmine), Sinatra, Ruby on Rails.

University of San Diego

Full Stack Web Development

B.B.A Marketing

B.A French

Sept. 2006 to May 2010